// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: "The worst-case occur in linear search algorithm when …….",
    answer: "Item is the last element in the array or item is not there at all",
    options: [
      "Item is somewhere in the middle of the array",
      "Item is not in the array at all",
      "Item is the last element in the array",
      "Item is the last element in the array or item is not there at all"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "If the number of records to be sorted is small, then …… sorting can be efficient.",
    answer: "Selection",
    options: [
      "Merge",
      "Heap",
      "Selection",
      "Bubble"
    ]
  },    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "Which of the following is not a limitation of binary search algorithm?",
    answer: "binary search algorithm is not efficient when the data elements more than 1500",
    options: [
        "must use a sorted array",
        "requirement of sorted array is expensive when a lot of insertion and deletions are needed",
        "there must be a mechanism to access middle element directly",
        "binary search algorithm is not efficient when the data elements more than 1500"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "The Average case occurs in the linear search algorithm ……….",
    answer: "when the item is somewhere in the middle of the array",
    options: [
        "when the item is somewhere in the middle of the array",
        "when the item is not the array at all",
        "when the item is the last element in the array",
        "Item is the last element in the array or item is not there at all"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Binary search algorithm cannot be applied to …",
    answer: "sorted linked list",
    options: [
        "sorted linked list",
        "sorted binary trees",
        "sorted linear array",
        "pointer array"
    ]
  },


    {
     numb: 6,
     question: "The complexity of merge sort algorithm is ……",
     answer: "O(n logn)",
     options: [
        "O(n)",
        "O(logn)",
        "O(n2)",
        "O(n logn)"
    ]
   },

   {
    numb: 7,
    question: "…………order is the best possible for array sorting algorithm which sorts n item.",
    answer: "O(n+logn)",
    options: [
        "O(n logn)",
        "O(n2)",
        "O(n+logn)",
        "O(logn)"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "Which of the following sorting algorithm is of divide and conquer type",
    answer: "Merge sort",
    options: [
        "Bubble sort",
        "Insertion sort",
        "Merge sort",
        "Selection sort"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "Partition and exchange sort is ……..",
    answer: "quick sort",
    options: [
        "quick sort",
        "tree sort",
        "heap sort",
        "bubble sort"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "The complexity of bubble sort algorithm is …..",
    answer: "O(n2)",
    options: [
        "O(n)",
        "O(logn)",
        "O(n2)",
        "O(n logn)"
    ]
  },

  // you can uncomment the below codes and make duplicate as more as you want to add question
  // but remember you need to give the numb value serialize like 1,2,3,5,6,7,8,9.....

];


